export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A speech in a play in which a character speaks his or her thoughts alone is",
A: "a monologue.",
B: "an aside.",
C: "a soliloquy.",
D: "an epilogue.",
answer: "C. soliloquy.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. In literature, repetition is used essentially for",
A: "rhyme.",
B: "suspense.",
C: "allusion.",
D: "emphasis.",
answer: "D. emphasis.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The pattern of a poem without reference to its content is referred to as the",
A: "limerick.",
B: "metre.",
C: "free verse.",
D: "form.",
answer: "D. form.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The performers in a play constitute the",
A: "chorus.",
B: "characters.",
C: "audience.",
D: "cast.",
answer: "D. cast.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The stanza is an example of",
A: "appellation.",
B: "apostrophe.",
C: "euphemism.",
D: "elegy.",
answer: "B. apostrophe. (Directly addressing Pan)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Pan is used here as",
A: "an allusion.",
B: "symbol.",
C: "irony.",
D: "metonymy.",
answer: "B. symbol. (Pan represents nature)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The rhyme scheme of the stanza is",
A: "abcabcc.",
B: "ababcdd.",
C: "babaccc.",
D: "bcbccaa.",
answer: "C. babaccc.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A metrical foot in which a stressed syllable is followed by an unstressed syllable is",
A: "iambic.",
B: "spondaic.",
C: "trochaic.",
D: "dactylic.",
answer: "A. iambic.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. ……..is the location of the action of the plot.",
A: "Setting",
B: "Narrative technique",
C: "Point of view",
D: "Characterization",
answer: "A. Setting",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A ballad is essentially a ………………….poem.",
A: "descriptive",
B: "dramatic",
C: "pastoral",
D: "narrative",
answer: "D. narrative",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The first four lines of the Shakespearean sonnet rhyme",
A: "abed.",
B: "abba.",
C: "abab.",
D: "eded.",
answer: "B. abba.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A story in which characters or actions represent abstract ideas or moral qualities is",
A: "an epic.",
B: "a legend.",
C: "an allegory.",
D: "a satire.",
answer: "C. an allegory.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The use of imagery in prose or verse",
A: "appeals to the senses.",
B: "develops the plot.",
C: "creates confusion.",
D: "obscures meaning.",
answer: "A. appeals to the senses.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The lines illustrate",
A: "soliloquy.",
B: "parallelism.",
C: "dialogue.",
D: "contrast.",
answer: "B. parallelism. (Parallel structure in the sentences)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. ‘heads’ in the second line is an example of",
A: "synecdoche.",
B: "inversion.",
C: "epithet.",
D: "conceit.",
answer: "A. synecdoche. ('heads' represents the people)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A character that develops in the course of a novel or play is described as",
A: "flat.",
B: "antagonist.",
C: "round.",
D: "protagonist.",
answer: "C. round.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A dirge is a poem sung",
A: "to send a child to sleep.",
B: "to make workers happy.",
C: "at a birthday party.",
D: "at a funeral.",
answer: "D. at a funeral.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. In drama, the……………………….creates humour.",
A: "hero",
B: "clown",
C: "villain",
D: "chorus",
answer: "B. clown",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Let me not love thee if I love thee not illustrates",
A: "metaphor.",
B: "proverb.",
C: "paradox.",
D: "meiosis.",
answer: "C. paradox. (A contradictory statement)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. is a literary device used to express something unpleasant in a more acceptable manner.",
A: "Epilogue",
B: "Epigram",
C: "Euphemism",
D: "Eulogy",
answer: "C. Euphemism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The writer’s attitude to the couple is one of",
A: "resignation.",
B: "indifference.",
C: "patronage.",
D: "praise.",
answer: "D. praise. (The description is full of warmth and appreciation)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The dominant literary device used in the passage is",
A: "litotes.",
B: "personification.",
C: "simile.",
D: "paradox.",
answer: "B. personification. (The pot 'willingly kept company,' the logs 'burned themselves out')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The rhetorical question that ends the passage stresses the",
A: "wickedness of thieves.",
B: "poverty of the couple.",
C: "security of the hut.",
D: "filthiness of the surroundings.",
answer: "C. security of the hut.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The expression such a rude room of such a poor pair illustrates",
A: "onomatopoeia",
B: "pun",
C: "rhyme",
D: "alliteration",
answer: "B. pun. ('rude room of such a poor pair')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The setting is",
A: "dawn.",
B: "sunset.",
C: "midday.",
D: "night.",
answer: "D. night. (Emphasis on keeping out the cold night air)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The rhyme scheme is",
A: "aabb ccdd eeff.",
B: "abab abab aabb.",
C: "abca abbe abab.",
D: "abba abca abab.",
answer: "B. abab abab aabb.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The theme of the poem is",
A: "the love of mother.",
B: "invoking the spirit of womanhood.",
C: "admiration for women’s hardwork.",
D: "the suffering of women.",
answer: "B. invoking the spirit of womanhood.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The literary device used in line 7 is",
A: "conceit.",
B: "personification.",
C: "hyperbole.",
D: "pathos.",
answer: "B. personification. ('God cause to shine on you His face')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The poet’s tone is one of",
A: "sadness.",
B: "joy.",
C: "condemnation.",
D: "sarcasm.",
answer: "B. joy.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. To bring forth sons and daughters brave illustrates",
A: "paradox.",
B: "zeugma.",
C: "inversion.",
D: "epigram.",
answer: "C. inversion. ('bring forth' instead of 'bring to birth')",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The speaker is",
A: "Gonzalo.",
B: "Antonio.",
C: "Prospero.",
D: "Alonso.",
answer: "A. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The addressee is",
A: "Ariel.",
B: "Ferdinand.",
C: "Caliban.",
D: "Miranda.",
answer: "A. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The imposter is",
A: "Sebastian.",
B: "Antonio.",
C: "Ferdinand.",
D: "Alonso.",
answer: "B. Hamlet.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The advocate and the impostor are",
A: "conspirators.",
B: "enemies.",
C: "suspicious of each other.",
D: "attracted to each other.",
answer: "D. anxious.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The speaker’s utterance betrays his",
A: "anger.",
B: "pretence.",
C: "hatred.",
D: "sorrow.",
answer: "C. strength and size.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The speaker is",
A: "Gonzalo.",
B: "Antonio.",
C: "Sebastian.",
D: "Alonso.",
answer: "B. Marcellus.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. these words refer to",
A: "the shipwreck.",
B: "the son’s disappearance.",
C: "the daughter’s wedding.",
D: "Prospero’s magic.",
answer: "A. Bernado.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Where did the wedding take place?",
A: "Algiers",
B: "Milan",
C: "Tunis",
D: "Naples",
answer: "B. ghost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The setting is",
A: "outside Prospero’s cell.",
B: "on a ship.",
C: "in front of Prospero’s cell.",
D: "another part of the island.",
answer: "A. frightening.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. …in my rate means",
A: "I’m very certain.",
B: "so far as I can see.",
C: "there’s no doubt.",
D: "as it appears.",
answer: "B. a platform in front of the castle.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Ariel has come because",
A: "he has been invited by Prospero.",
B: "he wants to make a request.",
C: "he desires a meeting.",
D: "flying is no problem to him.",
answer: "D. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Prospero has actually",
A: "raised a storm at sea.",
B: "punished Miranda.",
C: "dismissed Ferdinand.",
D: "commanded Ariel to disappear.",
answer: "A. exits.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Before Ariel’s entry,",
A: "Ferdinand has brought in some wood.",
B: "Prospero had put Miranda to sleep.",
C: "Caliban had been swearing at Prospero.",
D: "Trinculo had discovered Caliban’s cloak.",
answer: "D. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Ariel and all his quality means Ariel and",
A: "all at his command.",
B: "the quality of a spirit.",
C: "his band of spirits.",
D: "an ability to cause mischief.",
answer: "C. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Soon after, Ariel",
A: "flies off to do his duty.",
B: "recounts the confusion on board the ship.",
C: "kneel down to worship Prospero.",
D: "calls Ceres and another spirit.",
answer: "A. loyal madness. (Polonius hopes Ophelia's beauty will distract Hamlet from his melancholy)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. X and Y are",
A: "Antonio and Alonso.",
B: "Sebastian and Alonso.",
C: "Antonio and Gonzalo.",
D: "Sebastian and Gonzalo.",
answer: "B. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. We two are",
A: "Antonio and Adrian.",
B: "Sebastian and Adrian.",
C: "Sebastian and Francisco.",
D: "Antonio and Sebastian.",
answer: "A. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The situation in the extract is highly",
A: "satirical.",
B: "prophetic.",
C: "ironical.",
D: "comical.",
answer: "D. dead bodies.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. What has happened to all the other characters in the scene?",
A: "They have been made deaf and dumb.",
B: "Ariel has put them all to sleep.",
C: "They have been sent away.",
D: "Prospero has put them to sleep.",
answer: "C. Hamlet",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The two later plot to",
A: "kill all the other characters.",
B: "escape from the island.",
C: "kill Prospero and Miranda.",
D: "kill Alonso and Gonzalo.",
answer: "D. Laertes and the king.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]